

More than 10 years software development working experience with semiconductor industry vision application background. Strong C/C++ development and debugging skills. Experience of software design and leading of a team. Passionate about science, with strong technical, business, and interpersonal skills for working in a team and successfully completing a project.

## **Working Experience**

#### ASM Pacific Technology Ltd.

Hong Kong

Technical Manager

Jan. 2017-Present

As a software architect, I am responsible for system architecture design, task breakdown and follow-up, code review. Designed and implemented general AI segmentation system, portability system, event trace system, configurable image capture system, integrated script engine. The related technologies are task scheduling based on dependencies, code generation based on C++ template, design patterns, and code refactor.

### ASM Pacific Technology Ltd.

Hong Kong

Senior Software Engineer

Jan. 2012-2017

I was responsible for vision software architecture design, implementation and testing for raw solar wafer 3D inspection system. As the key developer, I fixed many software bugs and did performance tuning by profiling, algorithm optimization, caching strategy, thread pool and memory pool. Perform unit test and integration test. Analyze failure case and find solution.

Now I act as a supervisor for ATC vision application team, and also lead a application team in Hong Kong, the rules including requirement analysis, system design, task assignment, review and follow-up.

#### ASM Pacific Technology Ltd.

Hong Kong

Software Engineer

Apr. 2008-Jan. 2012

My roles includes collecting product group requirements, software design, implementation and testing for Post Encapsulation Product (PEP). I developed and enhanced some vision core features including mark inspection, kerf inspection, auto-lighting and auto model alignment. I also participated in the design and development of vision OO platform including alignment module, refactor system, serialization, criteria module developments.

Tencent ShenZhen

Software Engineer (Intern)

Feb. 2008-Apr. 2008

I was responsible to support internationalization and localization for a QQ game in International Product Center (IPC).

Ji'nan Yin Hu

Ji'nan

Software Engineer (Intern)

Jul. 2005-Sep. 2005

I was responsible for design and implement the water, electric, gas meter charges software for Department of Finance, Shandong Province. Collect customer requirements, design software architecture, implementation and testing.

## **Education**

## Academic Qualifications.....

Harbin Institute of Technology

Mphil Control Science and Engineering

**Shenzhen** 2005–2008

• Shandong University
• Beng Industry Automation

**Ji'nan** 2001–2005

# Notable Projects.

• Masters Project: Computer vision based mobile robot attitude and position estimation based on stereo vision

o Bachelor Project: Fingerprint image enhancement

## **Technical and Personal skills**

• **Programming Languages:** Proficient in: C, C++, Python, Matlab, Basic Basic ability with: Assembly, Java, Javascript, C#. I am very interested in Rust recently.

- OS: Working environment is Windows, and Linux (Mainly for AI training). I have setup a Respberry server in home.
- o **Certification:** Software Design Engineer (Advanced Programmer) Qualification. CET 4, CET 6 Qualification.
- o General Business Skills: Presentation skills, Works well in a team.